<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
 "reference.dtd">
<reference id="common-atts" xml:lang="en-us">
 <title>Other common attributes</title>
 <shortdesc>These common attributes are used across a wide variety of elements, with the common
    definition included below. These attributes are not defined as a group, and many elements only
    specify one or two from this list.</shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>other common attribute group</indexterm>
        <indexterm>attribute groups<indexterm>other common</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
 <refbody>
  <section id="section-1">
   <dl>
        <dlentry id="anchorref" platform="dita">
          <dt><xmlatt>anchorref</xmlatt></dt>
          <dd>Identifies a location within another map file where this map will be anchored at
            runtime. Resolution of the map is deferred until the final step in the delivery of any
            rendered content. For example, <codeph>anchorref="map1.ditamap/a1"</codeph> causes this
            map to be pulled into the location of the anchor point "a1" inside
              <filepath>map1.ditamap</filepath> when <filepath>map1.ditamap</filepath> is rendered
            for delivery. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="compact" platform="dita">
          <dt><xmlatt>compact</xmlatt></dt>
          <dd>Indicates close vertical spacing between list items. Expanded spacing is the
            processing default. The output result of compact spacing depends on the processor or
            browser. Allowable values are: <dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>yes </dt>
                <dd>Indicates compact spacing. </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>no </dt>
                <dd>Indicates expanded spacing. </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry conkeyref="reuse-attributes/ditauseconref">
                <dt> </dt>
                <dd> </dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
    <dlentry id="keyref">
     <dt><xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt></dt>
     <dd><ph id="keyrefDescription"><xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> provides a redirectable reference based
              on a key defined within a map. See <xref keyref="attributes-keyref"/> for information
              on using this attribute. </ph></dd>
    </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="mapkeyref" platform="dita">
          <dt><xmlatt>mapkeyref</xmlatt></dt>
          <dd>Identifies the map, if any, from which the contained links or metadata are derived.
            This value <ph>might</ph> be automatically generated by a process that creates the links
            or metadata based on map context, as a way to identify which map the material came from.
            If the <xmlelement>linklist</xmlelement>, or <xmlelement>linkpool</xmlelement>, or
            metadata is manually created by an author, there is no need to use this attribute.
              <ph>Note that this attribute is not related to the <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute,
              and is not used for key based processing.</ph>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
    <dlentry id="xmlspace">
     <dt><xmlatt>xml:space</xmlatt></dt>
     <dd>This attribute is provided on <xmlelement>pre</xmlelement>, <xmlelement>lines</xmlelement>,
            and on elements specialized from those. It ensures that parsers in editors and
            transforms respect the white space, including line-end characters, that is part of the
            data in those elements. It is intended to be part of the default properties of these
            elements, and not for authors to change or delete. When defined, it has a fixed value of
            "preserve".</dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl>
  </section>
 </refbody>
</reference>

