<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="display-atts" xml:lang="en-us">
 <title>Display attribute group</title>
 <shortdesc>The display attribute group includes attributes whose values can be used for affecting
  the display of many elements.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <metadata>
   <keywords>
    <indexterm>display attribute group</indexterm>
    <indexterm>attribute groups<indexterm>display</indexterm></indexterm>
   </keywords>
  </metadata>
 </prolog>
 <refbody>
  <section id="section-1">
   <dl>
    <dlentry id="expanse">
     <dt><xmlatt>expanse</xmlatt></dt>
     <dd>Determines the horizontal placement of the element. Allowable values are: <dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>column </dt>
        <dd>Aligns the element with the current column margin.</dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>page </dt>
        <dd>Places the element on the left page margin for left-to-right presentation, or right page
         margin for right-to-left presentation.</dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>spread </dt>
        <dd>Indicates that, if possible, the object should be rendered across a multi-page spread.
         If the rendition target does not have anything corresponding to spreads then spread has the
         same meaning as <keyword>page</keyword>.</dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>textline </dt>
        <dd>Aligns the element with the left (for left to right presentation) or right (for right to
         left presentation) margin of the current text line and takes indention into account.</dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry conkeyref="reuse-attributes/ditauseconref"
        platform="dita">
        <dt> </dt>
        <dd> </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><p conkeyref="reuse-general/pgwide-explain" platform="dita"
       /><p>Some DITA processors or output formats might not be able to support all values.
      </p></dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry id="frame">
     <dt><xmlatt>frame</xmlatt></dt>
     <dd>Specifies which portion of a border should surround the element. Allowable values are: <dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>all </dt>
        <dd>Draw a box around the element </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>bottom </dt>
        <dd>Draw a line after the element </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>none </dt>
        <dd>Don&apos;t draw any lines around this element </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>sides </dt>
        <dd>Draw a line at each side of the element </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
       <dlentry>
        <dt>top </dt>
        <dd>Draw a line before the element </dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry>
        <dt><keyword>topbot</keyword>
        </dt>
        <dd>Draw a line both before and after the element </dd>
       </dlentry>
       <dlentry conkeyref="reuse-attributes/ditauseconref"
        platform="dita">
        <dt> </dt>
        <dd> </dd>
       </dlentry>
      </dl><p>Some DITA processors or output formats might not be able to support all values.
      </p></dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry id="scale">
     <dt><xmlatt>scale</xmlatt></dt>
     <dd>Specifies a percentage, selected from an enumerated list, that is used to resize fonts in
      relation to the normal text size. This attribute is primarily useful for print-oriented
      display. <p>The <xmlatt>scale</xmlatt> attribute provides an acknowledged style-based property
       directly on DITA elements. For the <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> and
        <xmlelement>fig</xmlelement> elements, the intent of the property is to allow authors to
       adjust font sizes on the content of the containing element, primarily for print
       accommodation. An <xmlelement>image</xmlelement> in these contexts is to be scaled only by
       its own direct scale property. If not specifically scaled, such an
        <xmlelement>image</xmlelement> is unchanged by the scale property of its parent
        <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> or <xmlelement>fig</xmlelement>. </p><p>Allowable values are
       50, 60, 70, 80, 90, 100, 110, 120, 140, 160, 180, 200, and <xref
        keyref="attributes-useconreftarget">-dita-use-conref-target</xref>. Some DITA processors or
       output formats might not be able to support all values. </p></dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl>
  </section>
 </refbody>
</reference>

