<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="example">
    <title>Example</title>
    <shortdesc>This section should be titled either "Example" or
    "Examples," depending on how many examples the section
    contains.</shortdesc>
    <conbody>
    <p>Consider the following guidelines for making the "Example" sections
      consistent across the specification</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Each code sample should be preceded by an explanatory paragraph
        that describes what the example illustrates. Use the following
        pattern: "The following code sample shows how X does Y:" If the
        intro paragraph contains a single sentence, it should end with a
        colon. If the intro paragraph contains more than one sentence, end
        it with a period.<p><b>Examples:</b></p><image placement="break"
          href="images/example-intro-sentence.jpg" scale="90"/><image
          placement="break" href="images/example-two-intro-sentences.jpg"
          scale="90"/></li>
      <li>The code sample should be indented two spaces. Use bold
        highlighting to call attention to the opening and closing
        tags.</li>
      <li>Code samples should be valid XML that can be copied-and-pasted
        into an editor (in the proper context). If ellipses are used to
        indicate missing information, surround them in an XML comment.</li>
      <li>(For sections with multiple examples) Begin with a paragraph that
        states "This section contains examples of how the
          <xmlelement>x</xmlelement> element can be used. Surround each
        introductory paragraph and code sample with a
          <xmlelement>figure</xmlelement> element that has a descriptive
        title.</li>
      <li>(For elements that are part of a larger structure, such as a
        table or definition list entry) Instead of containing an example,
        the section can have a cross reference to another topic. Use the
        following type of markup:
        <codeblock>&lt;p>See &lt;xref keyref="elements-x">&lt;xmlelement>x&lt;/xmlelement>&lt;/xref>.&lt;/p></codeblock></li>
      <li>For examples where you want to show possible rendering, use a
        screen capture with good alternate text. Do not just include
        markup, leaving the rendering up to whatever stylesheets are used
        when the output is generated. (Remember that the DITA specification
        often is republished by other businesses and organizations who use
        their own stylesheets.)</li>
      <li>Do your best to replace "faked" examples with content that would
        conceivably be production content.</li>
    </ul>
    </conbody>
</concept>
