<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="dita_learning_specialization_top" xml:lang="en-us"> 
  <title>A learning objects approach to learning and training content</title> 
  <shortdesc>The DITA learning and training specializations apply DITA
	 principles and best practices for using topic-based and modular content to
	 plan, develop, and deliver learning and training content. 
  </shortdesc> 
  <refbody> 
	 <section id="section_21048C94493142AAB6D0DCAD8BA132F2"> 
		<p>The reusable learning objects, or RLO, approach to learning content
		  derives from the pioneering work of learning content designers at several
		  companies, including Autodesk®, Oracle®, and Cisco®. Author Peder Jacobsen
		  defines an RLO as "a discrete reusable collection of content used to present
		  and support a single learning objective." With this approach, it is possible to
		  gather a pool of information objects and make them available for reuse and
		  repurposing in a variety of learning delivery contexts. 
		</p> 
		<p>There is a strong affinity between the DITA topic-based, modular
		  approach to content in general, and the learning objects approach to learning
		  content in particular. 
		</p> 
		<p>Working assumptions about learning content and how to support
		  authoring and delivering it with DITA include the following: 
		<ul id="ul_AA52726625414E7682DD19D4C7A07099"> 
		  <li id="li_B4F3020DA88542569FF296D43AD19985">The DITA Learning and
			 Training specialization builds on a reusable learning objects (RLO) approach to
			 learning content. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_61B03812FB804E6582F4074D86FB26DB">DITA 
			 <b>topic types</b> are the basic building blocks for learning objects
			 and specify the meaning and intention of content provided in instructional and
			 information objects. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_C21026924773449A9CFF626B5D63C493">DITA 
			 <b>domains</b> provide the mechanism for defining 
			 <i>interactions</i>, which can be used across the learning topic
			 types. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_97E164FECD5C49CAAEBE632D945379DE">DITA 
			 <b>domains</b> also provide the mechanism for defining learning 
			 <i>metadata</i>, which can be assigned either in topics or in maps. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_037B9427728D49BE86BF72E0857D5DD6">DITA 
			 <b>maps</b> arrange the DITA learning topics into a hierarchy of
			 learning objects and group such content for delivery as lessons, modules, and
			 courses. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_A4FC010A400B4C8299EFEE17BC63AE47">DITA 
			 <b>specialization 
			 </b>provides the mechanism for creating the learning-based topic
			 types, domains, and maps needed for instructional and information object
			 content requirements. 
		  </li> 
		</ul> 
		</p> 
		<fig id="fig_30A72A63126D4A519383585AC2F98C04"> 
		  <title>Learning objects and specialized DITA learning and training
			 topic types </title> 
		  <p>This figure shows the composition of learning objects as a)
			 instructional objects, b) information objects, and c) the specialized DITA
			 topic types to support them. 
		  </p> 
		  <image href="../../images/dita-learning-topics.png" placement="break"
			id="image_112D527732CD4A0BA50547852144CE55" scale="70" > 
			 <alt >Box diagram that shows the relationship
				between learning and training objects and the DITA-defined learning types that
				represent them. The Learning objects box shows instructional objects Overview,
				Content, Summary, and Assessments; the Content object is expanded in another
				box 'Information objects' including Concept, Task, Reference, Facts, Concepts,
				Procedures, and Principles. A DITA learning types box lists learningPlan,
				learningOverview, learningContent, learningSummary, and learningAssessment.
				Colors of the learning objects correlate to matching colors of the DITA
				learning types; for example, the Summary learning object and the
				learningSummary DITA type are both colored gold. 
			 </alt> 
		  </image> 
		  <p>In this approach, a learning object comprises a "discrete reusable
			 collection of content used to present and support a single learning objective,"
			 and consists of two primary information components: 
		  <ul id="ul_2A4493D1CA3F4D59B86C8E39A425DCE2"> 
			 <li id="li_60CF8922DF1B4885B62EE09255483C2F"><b>instructional
				  objects</b>, which provide the structured framework for a learning experience.
				The <xmlelement>learningOverview</xmlelement>,
				<xmlelement>learningSummary</xmlelement>, and
				<xmlelement>learningAssessment</xmlelement> topic types provide content for
				instructional objects. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_41587C58D186445087BE5C1A1F38CB03"><b>information
				  objects</b>, which provide the source learning content - the topic-based
				learning content and other supplemental content that supports the learning
				goals identified in the instructional objects. The
				<xmlelement>learningContent</xmlelement> topic type provides content for
				information objects. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_8C4D488C142F4D1F969678DF590E9132"><b>instructional
				  plans</b>, which identify the learning goals, needs, and objectives. The
				<xmlelement>learningPlan</xmlelement> topic type provides content for
				instructional plans. 
			 </li> 
		  </ul> 
		  </p> 
		</fig> 
		<fig id="fig_FF53D171597B42EFB3AA8A6BC0EB51D5"> 
		  <title>Learning content design, authoring, and delivery through DITA
			 specialization</title> 
		  <p>This picture shows the end-to-end process for designing, authoring,
			 and delivering specialized learning content with DITA. 
			 <image href="../../images/dita-learning-e2e.png"
			  placement="break" id="image_B74B31D15151459CAAA35FF75355EFCB" scale="70"
			  > 
				<alt >Labeled flowchart-style diagram; across
				  the middle horizontally are four primary stages of the flowchart with arrows
				  from stage to stage. Across the top and bottom are 5 numbered labels, pointing
				  to locations in the 4 stages, with text explaining what happens at each stage.
				  (See text content following diagram.) The first stage shows a miniature tree
				  diagram signifying a hierarchically-structured set of DITA topics. The second
				  stage shows a collection of file objects signifying learning topics. The third
				  stage shows a tree structure diagram as well as a table diagram. The fourth
				  stage lists the following learning deliverable types: Tutorials, Courseware
				  &amp; e-learning, ILTs, CBTs, WBTs, SCORMS. 
				</alt> 
			 </image> 
		  </p> 
		  <p>In this approach, a learning content developer: 
		  <ol id="ol_F4EBF55C7E1F4F2FA3AF125CB9B4C48F"> 
			 <li id="li_46FDA726F1AB4A02AB0AEEA97B7CBA31">Uses 
				<b>learning map elements</b> to identify the learning objects and
				the supporting content needed to address specific learning goals and
				objectives. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_BE308AB15A0C4DB68F8638E4510D488C">Uses 
				<b>learning topic elements</b> to structure the learning content. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_4D303F003D44444E9C331A42E00AE306">Applies 
				<b>learning metadata elements</b> to describe specific
				characteristics of the learning content, following a sub-set of the IEEE LOM
				standard. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_4CC8A072116F4D05816879720D053B70">Constructs 
				<b>specific build maps and relationship tables</b> to organize
				learning objects for delivery as a course with specific output and delivery
				needs. 
			 </li> 
			 <li id="li_EA2BEA026A194102A284F1769660D3C4">Invokes 
				<b>processing</b> to generate specific learning deliverables, based
				on the default processing available with DITA content and specialized as needed
				for learning-specific purposes and delivery formats. 
			 </li> 
		  </ol> 
		  </p> 
		</fig> 
	 </section> 
  </refbody> 
</reference> 
