<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="conref-short-descriptions">
 <title>Short descriptions reused with LwDITA</title>
  <!--KJE: The topic contains short descriptions for the intersections topics that ONLY share a shortdesc. If a topic shares more than a shortdesc, create a reuse topic.-->
 <!-- KJE: Ensure that the shortdesc are ordered alphabetically by element name. Use the element name as the value of the @id attribute. -->
 <abstract>
    <shortdesc id="alt"> Alternate text is a textual description of an image. Systems can display
      the alternate text when the image cannot be rendered or viewed by the reader.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="b">Bold text is used to draw a reader's attention to a phrase without otherwise
      adding meaning to the content.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="body">The body contains the main content of a topic.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="dd">The definition description is the definition for a term in a definition list
      entry. </shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="dl">A definition list is a list of terms and corresponding
      definitions.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="dlentry">A definition list entry is a group within a definition list. It
      associates a term with its definition.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="dt">A definition term is the term or phrase that is defined in a definition list
      entry.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="fig">A figure is a container for a variety of objects, including artwork, images,
      code samples, equations, and tables.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="i">Italic text is used to emphasize the key points in printed text, or when
      quoting a speaker, a way to show which words the speaker stressed.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="li">A list item is an item in either an ordered or unordered list.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="ol">An ordered list is a list of items that are sorted by sequence or order of
      importance.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="p">A paragraph is a single unit of text that contains a main idea.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="prolog">The prolog contains metadata about the topic, for example, author
      information or subject category.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="simpletable">Simple tables are tables that are regular in structure and do not
      need a caption. </shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="stentry">A simple table entry represents a single cell within a simple
      table.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="sthead">A simple table header is an optional header row for a simple
      table.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="strow">A simple table row is a single row in a simple table.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="sub">A subscript is text that is printed below the line. It is frequently used in
      chemical and mathematical formulas.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="sup">A superscript is text that is printed above the line. It is frequently used
      in chemical and mathematical formulas.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="title">A title is a heading or label for an object. Titles can be associated with
      topics, maps, sections, examples, figures, tables, and other structures.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="topic">A topic is a standalone unit of information.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="topicref">A topic reference is the mechanism for referencing a topic (or another
      resource) from a DITA map. It can nest, which enables the expression of navigation and
      table-of-content hierarchies, as well as containment hierarchies and parent-child
      relationships.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="u">An underline, also called an underscore, is a line immediately below a portion
      of text. </shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="ul">An unordered list is a list in which the order of items is not significant. </shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="video">Video objects reference moving visual media.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="video-poster"> Video poster settings control the image that is rendered before video playback
      begins.</shortdesc>
    <shortdesc id="xref">A cross reference is an inline link. A cross reference can link to a
      different location within the current topic, another topic, a specific location in another
      topic, or an external resource such as a PDF or Web page.</shortdesc>
  </abstract>
</concept>
