<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="conref-short-descriptions">
 <title>Short descriptions reused with LwDITA</title>
 <!-- KJE: Ensure that the shortdesc are ordered alphabetically by element name. Use the element name as the value of the @id attribute. -->
 <abstract>
  <shortdesc id="alt">Alternate text is a textual description of an image that can be read
   or displayed in place of the image. This is commonly used to create text alternatives for readers
   or systems that cannot view the original image.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="b">Bold text is used to draw a reader's attention to a phrase without
   otherwise adding meaning to the content.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="body">The body contains the main content of a topic.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="data">Data is a generic component that represents metadata within a DITA topic or
   map. Complex metadata is represented by nested data structures.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="dd">The definition description provides the definition for a term in a definition
   list entry. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="desc">A description is a statement that describes or contains additional
   information about an object.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="dl">A definition list is a list of terms and corresponding definitions.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="dlentry">A definition list entry groups a term and its definition.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="dt">A definition term is the text that is defined in a definition list
   entry.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="fig">A figure is a container for a variety of objects, including artwork, images,
   code samples, equations, and tables.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="fn">The <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element specifies content for an ancillary note
   placed in the footer of a page or at the end of an online article. Such content is usually
   inappropriate for inline inclusion. The <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element also is used to
   indicate the source for facts or other material cited in the text. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="i"> Italic text is a way to emphasize the key points in printed text, or when
   quoting a speaker, a way to show which words the speaker stressed.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="image">An image is a reference to artwork that is stored outside of the content. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="keydef"><draft-comment author="robander">Need to take care when converting this to
    use natural language; our definition of the "key definition" as an element has to be distinct
    from our concept of a "key defintion" in the DITA architecture.</draft-comment>The
    <xmlelement>keydef</xmlelement> element is a convenience element that is used to define keys
   without any of the other effects that occur when using a <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement>
   element: no content is included in output, no title is included in the table of contents, and no
   linking or other relationships are defined. The <xmlelement>keydef</xmlelement> element is not
   the only way to define keys; its purpose is to simplify the process by defaulting several
   attributes to achieve the described behaviors.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="li">A list item is an item in either an ordered or unordered list.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="linktext">Link text is the label for a link or resource.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="map">The <xmlelement>map</xmlelement> element describes the relationships among a
   set of resources, such as DITA topics. Maps consist of references to topics, maps, and other
   resources organized into hierarchies, groups, and tables. Maps express these relationships in a
   single common format that can be used for different outputs. <draft-comment
    author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="20 June 2018">
    <p>This is very abstract ...</p>
   </draft-comment></shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="navtitle">A navigation title provides a title for a resource. When used in topics,
   it is an alternate title that is designed for situations when the topic title is unsuitable for
   use in a table of contents or navigation pane. When used in maps, a navigation title can serve as
   an alternate title or simply as an aid to understanding the DITA map.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="note">A note contains information that expands on or calls attention to a
   particular point.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="ol">An ordered list is a list of items that are sorted by sequence or order of
   importance.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="p"> A paragraph is a single unit of text that contain a main idea.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="ph">The <xmlelement>ph</xmlelement> element is used to enclose a phrase for reuse or
   conditional processing (for example, when part of a paragraph applies to a particular audience).
   It can be used by specializations of DITA to create semantic markup for content at the phrase
   level, which then allows (but does not require) specific processing or formatting.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="pre">Preformatted text is text that contains line breaks and spaces that are
   intended to be preserved at publication time.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="prolog">The prolog contains information about the topic, for example, author
   information or subject category. This information might be entered by an author or maintained by
   an application.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="section">A section is an organizational division in a topic. Sections are used to
   organize subsets of information that are directly related to the topic; they can be
   titled.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="shortdesc">A short description describes the purpose or main point of a
   topic.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="simpletable">Simple tables are tables that are regular in structure and do not need
   a caption. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="stentry">A simple table entry represents a single cell within a simple
   table.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="sthead">A simple table header is a header row for a simple table.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="strow">A simple table row is a single row in a simple table.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="sub">A subscript is a letter, number, or figure that is printed lower than the
   line. It is frequently used in chemical and mathematical formulas.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="sup">A superscript is a letter, number, or figure that is printed above than the
   line. It is frequently used in chemical and mathematical formulas; it also is used for
   footnotes.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="title">A title is a heading or label for an object. Titles can be associated with
   topics, maps, sections, examples, figures, and tables.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="topic">A topic is a standalone unit of information.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="topicmeta">Topic metadata is metadata that applies to a topic; this metadata is
   defined in a map. This metadata also applies to other topics in the map that are part of the same
   containment hierarchy</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="topicref">A topic reference is the mechanism for referencing a topic from a DITA
   map. It can nest, which enables the expression of navigation and table-of-content hierarchies, as
   well as containment hierarchies and parent-child relationships.</shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="u">An underline, also called an underscore, is a more or less horizontal line
   immediately below a portion of writing. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="ul">An unordered is a list of items in which the order of list items is not
   significant. </shortdesc>
  <shortdesc id="xref">A cross reference is a link to a different location within the current topic,
   another topic, a specific location in another topic, or an external resource such as a PDF or Web
   page.</shortdesc>
 </abstract>
</concept>
