<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="accessibilitymarkup" xml:lang="en-US">
	<title>Accessible tables</title>
	<shortdesc>The complex nature of table rendering requires authors and
    processors to be aware of several DITA elements and attributes. This
    topic describes common accessibility guidelines that are related to
    tables, along with the DITA markup that is designed to support
    them.</shortdesc>
	<prolog>
		<metadata>
			<keywords>
				<indexterm>accessibility<indexterm>tables</indexterm></indexterm>
			</keywords>
		</metadata>
	</prolog>
	<conbody>
		<section id="tables">
      <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="28 March 2022">
        <p>This topic needs a more extensive edit than I did,
          including:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Ensuring that the vocabulary aligns with how we describe
            complex and simple tables in the element-reference topics</li>
          <li>Introducing the content outlined in the definition list</li>
          <li>Alphabeticizing the entries in the definition list</li>
          <li>Recasting the wording for the column headers and irregular
            headers to focus on what can be done with markup, instead of
            specifying what an author should do</li>
        </ul>
      </draft-comment>
			<p>DITA provides two table models, a more complex one using the
          <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element and the other using
          <xmlelement>simpletable</xmlelement>. The
          <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element is based on the OASIS
        Exchange Table Model, while the
          <xmlelement>simpletable</xmlelement> element reflects a simpler
        model that is closer to an HTML table. Each table model is
        addressed here. For some cases, such as a table with two header
        rows or two header columns, the more complex
          <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element needs to be used.</p>
			<dl>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Captions</dt>
					<dd>Both table models allow for a caption using the
							<xmlelement>title</xmlelement> element.</dd>
				</dlentry>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Summaries</dt>
					<dd>While the <xmlatt>summary</xmlatt> attribute on tables is
            deprecated in HTML5, the <xmlelement>desc</xmlelement> element
            within a <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> can be used to store a
            summary. The description is also often used for rendered
            content about the table, so processors might need to be
            configured to support this use.</dd>
				</dlentry>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Header rows</dt>
					<dd>When using a <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element, one or more header rows can be
						specified in the <xmlelement>thead</xmlelement> element. <p>When using a
								<xmlelement>simpletable</xmlelement> element, the header row can be
							placed in a <xmlelement>sthead</xmlelement> element.</p></dd>
				</dlentry>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Table column headers (first column)</dt>
					<dd>When using a <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element, set the <xmlatt>rowheader</xmlatt>
						attribute to <keyword>firstcol</keyword> on the
							<xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element to indicate that the first column
						is a header. Alternatively, set the <xmlatt>scope</xmlatt> attribute in the
						first entry in the first row to <keyword>col</keyword>, indicating that it
						is a header for the entire column.<p>When using a
								<xmlelement>simpletable</xmlelement> element, set the
								<xmlatt>keycol</xmlatt> attribute to <keyword>1</keyword>.</p></dd>
				</dlentry>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Table column headers (other columns)</dt>
					<dd>When using a <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> element, use the
            column specifications (<xmlelement>colspec</xmlelement>) to
            define which columns function as headers. For that case, set
            the attribute <xmlelement>rowheader</xmlelement> to
              <keyword>headers</keyword> on the column or columns that
            function as headers. Alternatively, set the
              <xmlatt>scope</xmlatt> attribute on each relevant entry in
            the first row to <keyword>col</keyword>, indicating that the
            entry is a header for the entire column.<p>When using a
                <xmlelement>simpletable</xmlelement> element, set the
                <xmlatt>keycol</xmlatt> attribute to the number of the
              column that functions as a header.</p></dd>
				</dlentry>
				<dlentry>
					<dt>Irregular header cells within a table</dt>
					<dd>When entries within a table function as headers, but do not fall
            into the row or column descriptions above, the
              <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> and <xmlatt>headers</xmlatt> attributes
            on <xmlelement>table</xmlelement> entries can be used to relate
            any entry to the header. Set the <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute
            on the cell that functions as a header, and set the
              <xmlatt>headers</xmlatt> attribute to that ID value on any
            entry for which it acts as a header.</dd>
				</dlentry>
			</dl>
		</section>
	</conbody>
</concept> 
