<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="accessibility_contentvsprocessor">
    <title>Handling accessibility in content and in processors</title>
    <shortdesc>Accessibility requirements vary depending on how content is
    rendered. These requirements fall on both content owners and on the
    processors that render DITA content.</shortdesc>
    <conbody>
        <p>One of the best known standards for producing accessible content
      is the set of <xref href="https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG21/"
        format="html" scope="external">Web Content Accessibility Guidelines
        (WCAG)</xref> from W3C. While content formats and content owners
      might always have unique or additional accessibility needs, the rules
      in outline in the WCAG provide a reference point for considering how
      to create accessible content in DITA.</p>
        <p>When considering how to work with DITA, the guidelines fall into
      several categories:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>General content guidelines</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Many accessibility guidelines and best practices apply to
              all content. Such guidelines are generally outside the scope
              of this specification. </p>
            <p>For example, a guideline might recommend against multiple
              levels of nested unordered lists, because such lists are
              difficult to navigate with a screen reader. As a general
              content standard, DITA cannot prohibit such nesting. However,
              implementations can prevent such nesting through business
              processes or rule-based processing such as Schematron.</p>
            <p>Another common accessibility recommendation is to avoid
              flashing or flickering video content. The DITA
                <xmlelement>video</xmlelement> element is a general
              mechanism for including any video, and the content of that
              video is outside the scope of this specification.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Markup guidelines</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Many other accessibility guidelines require use of specific
              DITA markup. Such guidelines are addressed in the
              specification.</p>
            <p>For example, a requirement that images specify alternate
              text requires use of the <xmlelement>alt</xmlelement> element
              within an image. However, a guideline that the alternate text
              be <i>meaningful</i> is not something that can be enforced by
              DITA markup.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Guidelines that require enablement by DITA processors</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Some accessibility guidelines require processors to take
              advantage of specific DITA markup.</p>
            <p>Authors can use specific markup to enable accessible output.
              For example, by placing a header row in a table using
                <xmlelement>thead</xmlelement> or
                <xmlelement>sthead</xmlelement>, an author can define a
              header for every cell in the table body. However, to make the
              relationship between the table cell and header cell specific
              in a rendered format like HTML, the processor must make those
              relationships explicit in the output</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Processor requirements outside the scope of DITA markup</dt>
          <dd>Processors have many other accessibility concerns that are
            outside the scope of this specification.<p>For example, WCAG
              has a requirement for contrast ratios when rendering text
              content. That requirement is unrelated to the source content.
              Such requirements apply to rendering tools such as the CSS
              that is used to style DITA content in a browser.</p><p>As
              another example, a DITA processor might generate automated
              headings or text strings, such as a greater-than character
              (>) that is used between DITA phrases that are identified as
              a part of a menu navigation. It is up to the processor to use
              correct rendering for these cases, such as heading markup and
              accessible text alternatives for character displays such as
              the menu separator.</p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
