<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="accessibility_contentvsprocessor">
    <title>Handling accessibility in content and in processors</title>
    <shortdesc>Accessibility requirements vary depending on how content is
    rendered. Making content accessible is work that involves both content
    authors and the processors that render DITA content.</shortdesc>
    <conbody>
        <p><ph rev="review-o">The foundation for accessible content is
        the</ph> Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) from W3C.
      While content formats and content authors might have unique or
      additional accessibility needs, the rules outlined in the WCAG
      provide a reference point for considering how to create accessible
      content in DITA.</p>
        <p>The guidelines fall into several categories:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>General content guidelines</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>Many accessibility guidelines and best practices apply to all
            content. Such guidelines are generally outside the scope of
            this specification. </p>
          <p>For example, a guideline might recommend against multiple
            levels of nested unordered lists, because such lists are
            difficult to navigate with a screen reader. As a general
            content standard, DITA cannot prohibit such nesting. However,
            implementations can prevent such nesting through business
            processes or rule-based processing such as Schematron.</p>
          <p>Another common accessibility recommendation is to avoid
            flashing or flickering video content. The DITA
              <xmlelement>video</xmlelement> element is a general mechanism
            for including video, and the content of that video is outside
            the scope of this specification.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Markup guidelines</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>Other accessibility guidelines require <ph rev="review-o"
              >the</ph> use of specific DITA markup. Such guidelines are
            addressed in this specification.</p>
          <p>For example, a requirement that images specify alternate text
            requires <ph rev="review-o">the</ph> use of the
              <xmlelement>alt</xmlelement> element within <ph
              rev="review-o">the <xmlelement>image</xmlelement>
              element</ph>. However, a guideline that the alternate text be
              <i>meaningful</i> is not something that can be enforced by
            DITA markup.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Guidelines that require enablement by DITA processors</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>Some accessibility guidelines require processors to take
            advantage of specific DITA markup.</p>
          <p>Authors can use specific markup to enable accessible output. For example, by specifying
            a header row in a table, an author can define a header for every cell in the table body.
            However, to make the relationship between the table cell and header cell specific in a
            rendered format like HTML, the processor must make those relationships explicit in the
            output.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Processor requirements outside the scope of DITA markup</dt>
        <dd>Processors have many other accessibility concerns that are
          outside the scope of this specification.<p>For example, WCAG has
            a requirement for contrast ratios when rendering <ph
              rev="review-o">substantive</ph> content. That requirement is
            unrelated to the source content. Such requirements apply to
            rendering mechanisms such as the CSS that is used to style DITA
            content in a browser.</p><p>As another example, a DITA
            processor might generate automated headings or include
            characters in output, such as:</p><ul>
            <li>A section heading for an element specialized from
                <xmlelement>section</xmlelement>, such as
                <keyword>Requirements</keyword> for the
                <xmlelement>prereq</xmlelement> element in a task
              topic</li>
            <li>The greater-than character (>) that is typically used
              between phrases that are part of a menu navigation</li>
          </ul><p>It is up to the processor to use correct rendering for
            these cases, such as heading markup and accessible text
            alternatives for character displays such as the menu
            separator.</p></dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
    </conbody>
</concept>
