<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="filtering">
 <title>Filtering</title>
 <shortdesc>At processing time, a conditional processing profile can be used to specify profiling
  attribute values that determine whether an element with those values is included or
  excluded.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>By default, values in conditional processing attributes that are not defined in a DITAVAL
   profile evaluate to "include". For example, if the value audience="novice" is used on a
   paragraph, but this value is not defined in a DITAVAL profile, the attribute evaluates to
   "include".</p>
  <p>However, the DITAVAL profile can change this default to "exclude", so that any value not
   explicitly defined in the DITAVAL profile will evaluate to "exclude". The DITAVAL profile also
   can be used to change the default for a single attribute; for example, it can declare that values
   in the <xmlatt>platform</xmlatt> attribute default to "exclude", while those in the
    <xmlatt>product</xmlatt> attribute default to include. See <xref
    href="../../langRef/containers/ditaval-elements.dita"/> for information on how to set up a
   DITAVAL profile and how to change default behaviors.</p>
  <p>When deciding whether to include or exclude a particular element, a processor evaluates each
   attribute independently:</p>
  <ol>
   <li>For each attribute:<ul>
<li >If the attribute is empty, or contains only empty groups, it is equivalent
to omitting the attribute from the element. If evaluated for the purposes of filtering, the
attribute is treated as "include", because an omitted attribute cannot evaluate to "exclude".</li>
     <li>If the attribute value does not contain any groups, then if any token in the attribute
      value evaluates to "include", the element evaluates to "include"; otherwise it evaluates to
      "exclude". In other words, the attribute evaluates to "exclude" only when <b>all</b> the
      values in that attribute evaluate to "exclude".</li>
     <li >If the attribute value does include groups, evaluate as
      follows, treating ungrouped tokens together as a group: <ol>
       <li>For each group (including the group of ungrouped tokens), if any token inside the group
        evaluates to "include", the group evaluates to "include"; otherwise it evaluates to
        "exclude". In other words, a group evaluates to "exclude" only when every token in that
        group evaluates to "exclude".</li>
       <li>If any group within an attribute evaluates to "exclude", that attribute evaluates to
        "exclude"; otherwise it evaluates to "include".</li>
      </ol></li>
    </ul></li>
   <li>If <b>any single attribute</b> evaluates to exclude, the element is excluded.</li>
  </ol>
  <!--<draft-comment author="Kristen Eberlein" time="8 February 2014">We need to make this wording more precise and less ambiguous. Is the following content what was intended?<ul><li>(For an attribute with a single value) If the attribute value is set to "exclude", the element is excluded.</li><li>(For an attribute with multiple values) If all the attribute values are set to "exclude", the element is excluded</li><li>(For an attribute with a single group of values) If all the attribute values in the group are set to "exclude", the element is excluded.</li></ul>I'm not sure I understand what is meant by "When deciding whether to include or exclude a particular element, a processor should evaluate each attribute, and then evaluate the set of attributes." What's the difference between evaluating each attribute and evaluating a set of attributes?</draft-comment><draft-comment author="robander" time="21 April 2014">I think that is resolved now. I've tweaked the wording a bit - the list in the previous draft comment was not correct.</draft-comment>-->
  <p>For example, if a paragraph applies to three products and the publisher has chosen to exclude
   all of them, the processor will exclude the paragraph. This is true even if the paragraph applies
   to an audience or platform that is not excluded. But if the paragraph applies to an additional
   product that has not been excluded, then its content is still relevant for the intended output
   and is preserved.</p>
  <p >Similarly, with groups, a step might apply to one application
   server and two database applications:
   <codeblock id="groupcodesample">&lt;steps>
  &lt;step>&lt;cmd>Common step&lt;/cmd>&lt;/step>
  &lt;step product="appserver(mySERVER) database(ABC dbOtherName)">
    &lt;cmd>Do something special for databases ABC or OtherName when installing on mySERVER&lt;/cmd>
  &lt;/step>
  &lt;!-- additional steps -->
&lt;/steps></codeblock></p>
  <p>If a publisher decides to exclude the application server mySERVER, then the appserver() group
   evaluates to exclude. This can be done by setting <codeph>product="mySERVER"</codeph> to exclude
    <i>or</i> by setting <codeph>appserver="mySERVER"</codeph> to exclude. This means the step is
   excluded, regardless of how the values "ABC" or "dbOtherName" evaluate. If a rule is specified
   for both <codeph>product="mySERVER"</codeph> and <codeph>appserver="mySERVER"</codeph>, the rule
   for the more specific group name "appserver" takes precedence.</p>
  <p>Similarly, if both "ABC" and "dbOtherName" evaluate to exclude, then the database() group
   evaluates to exclude and the element is excluded regardless of how the "mySERVER" value is
   set.</p>
  <p >In more advanced usage, a DITAVAL can be used to specify a rule
   for a group name. For example, an author could create a DITAVAL rule that sets
    <codeph>product="database"</codeph> to "exclude". This is equivalent to setting a default of
   "exclude" for any individual value in a database() group; it also excludes the more common usage
   of "database" as a single value within the <xmlatt>product</xmlatt> attribute. Thus when "myDB"
   appears in a database() group within the <xmlatt>product</xmlatt> attribute, the full precedence
   for determining whether to include or exclude the value is as follows: <ol>
    <li>Check for a DITAVAL rule for <codeph>database="myDB"</codeph></li>
    <li>Check for a DITAVAL rule for <codeph>product="myDB"</codeph></li>
    <li>Check for a DITAVAL rule for <codeph>product="database"</codeph> (default for the database
     group)</li>
    <li>Check for a DITAVAL rule for "product" (default for the <xmlatt>product</xmlatt>
     attribute)</li>
    <li>Check for a default rule for all conditions (default of include or exclude for all
     attributes)</li>
    <li>Otherwise, evaluate to "include"</li>
   </ol></p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
