<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="merging-index-elements">
    <title>Merging index elements</title>
    <shortdesc>Processors merge indexing elements in order to construct the effective index for a
        publication.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm>processing expectations<indexterm>indexing<indexterm>matching
                            content</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>processing
                        expectations<indexterm>indexing<indexterm>merging</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p>Processors <term outputclass="RFC-2119">SHOULD</term> use the following criteria to match
            the content of <xmlelement>indexterm</xmlelement> elements:<ul>
                <li>Ignore leading and trailing whitespace, as well as newline characters</li>
                <li>Be case sensitive</li>
                <li/>
            </ul></p>
        <p>It is implementation-dependent as to whether processors consider the presence of
            phrase-level markup within <xmlelement>indexterm</xmlelement> elements when performing a
            matching operation.</p>
        <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="11 August 2019">
            <p>This is a new topic. It needs to lay out the rules and expectations for how a
                processor merges indexing elements and constructs the effective index,
                including:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Matching the content of indexing elements</li>
                <li>Constructing multilevel index entries (as suggested in <xref
                        href="example-of-nested-indexterm-elements.dita"/>)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>What are other critical aspects?</p>
        </draft-comment>
        <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="08 July 2019">
            <p>Do we make the following RFC-2119 statement for DITA 2.0. Thoughts?</p>
            <p>FYI, the following text appeared in the DITA 1.1 - 1.3 specs: <q>All indexterms with
                    the same content are ″merged″ to form a single index entry in the resulting
                    index, and all contributed page numbers are included in that index
                entry.</q></p>
        </draft-comment>
        <p>(For processors that support indexing) If multiple <xmlelement>indexterm</xmlelement>
            elements exist that would result in matchingl index entries, a processor <term
                outputclass="RFC-2119">SHOULD</term> generate only a single index entry, although
            all locations associated with the <xmlelement>indexterm</xmlelement> element contribute
            locators.</p>
        <draft-comment author="Eliot Kimber" time="09 August 2019">
            <p>This is the correct behavior. By "identical content" is a little too strict. Probably
                need to say something like "content that the processor considers to be the same. For
                example, by normalizing white space."</p>
        </draft-comment>
        <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="13 August 2019">
            <p>Eliot raised the following scenario in his review of the indexing content:</p>
            <p>Consider a publication that contains the following index markup in different
                topics:</p>
            <codeblock>&lt;!-- Topic A -->
&lt;indexterm>apple&lt;/indexterm>

&lt;!-- Topic B -->
&lt;indexterm>apple
  &lt;indexterm>computer&lt;/indexterm>
&lt;/indexterm></codeblock>
            <p>What would the author of topic A expect to see in the index? What would the author of
                topic B expect to see? How might this combine with indexing markup added at the map
                level by the map owner?</p>
            <p>Eliot suggested that a processor might produce any of the following (arrow character
                used to indicate  indentation):</p>
            <lines><b>Option #1</b>
apple 12
&#x362;computer 14

<b>Option #2</b>
apple 12
apple
&#x362;computer 14

<b>
Option #3</b>
apple
&#x362;computer 14
</lines>
            <p>My personal expectation would be to expect to see option #1, which matches the
                statement made in the DITA 1.1-1.3 specs: <q>All indexterms with the same content
                    are ″merged″ to form a single index entry in the resulting index, and all
                    contributed page numbers are included in that index entry.</q></p>
            <p>If a company's styleguide does not want locators on parents of leaf nodes, I'd expect
                authors to spend time "massaging" index markup in order to generate an index that
                followed the styleguide requirements.</p>
        </draft-comment>
    </conbody>
</concept>
