<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="processing_key_references">
    <title><ph >Processing key references for navigation links and images</ph></title>
    <shortdesc>Keys can be used to create or redirect links and cross references. Keys also can be
        used to address resources such as images or videos. This topic explains how to evaluate key
        references on links and cross references to determine a link target. </shortdesc>
    <conbody>
        <p>When a key definition is bound to a resource that is addressed by the
                <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attributes, and does not specify
            "none" for the <xmlatt>linking</xmlatt> attribute, all references to that key definition
            become links to the bound resource. When a key definition is not bound to a resource or
            specifies "none" for the <xmlatt>linking</xmlatt> attribute, references to that key
            definition do not become links.</p>
        <p>When a key definition has no <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> value and no <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt>
            value, references to that key will not result in a link, even if they do contain an
                <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> attribute of their own. If the key definition also does not
            contain a <xmlelement>topicmeta</xmlelement> subelement, empty elements that refer to
            the key (such as <codeph>&lt;link keyref="a"/></codeph> or <codeph>&lt;xref keyref="a"
                href="fallback.dita"/></codeph>) are <ph >ignored</ph>.</p>
        <p>The <xmlelement>object</xmlelement> element has an additional key-referencing attribute
            named <xmlatt>datakeyref</xmlatt>. Key names in this attribute are resolved using the
            same processing that is described for the normal <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute.</p>
        <!--<p>For key references to undefined keys, if there is an @href attribute
on         the referencing element, the value of the @href attribute
is used as the         reference and the key reference element is
processed as if there were no key reference. If         the key reference
element does not specify @href, the element is not
        treated as a navigation link. It is an error for the element
to be empty, and an         implementation <keyword>may</keyword> give
an error message, and <keyword>may</keyword>         recover from
this error condition by leaving the key reference element empty. </p>-->
    </conbody>
</concept>
