<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="rng-requirements-overview">
 <title>RELAX NG: Overview of coding requirements</title>
 <shortdesc>RELAX NG modules are self-integrating; they automatically add to the content models and
  attribute lists that they extend. This means that information architects do not have much work to
  do when integrating vocabulary modules <ph rev="2.0">and element-configuration modules
   (constraints and expansion)</ph> into document-type shells.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <metadata>
   <keywords>
    <indexterm>coding
     requirements<indexterm>RNG<indexterm>overview</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
    <indexterm>RNG<indexterm>coding
     requirements<indexterm>overview</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
   </keywords>
  </metadata>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p>In addition to simplifying document-type shells, the self-integrating aspect of RELAX NG
   results in the following coding practices:</p>
  <ul>
   <li>Each specialization module consists of a single file, unlike the two required for DTDs.</li>
   <li>Domain modules directly extend elements, unlike DTDs, which rely on an extra file and
    extensions within the document-type shell.</li>
   <li>Constraint modules directly include the modules that they extend, which means that just by
    referencing a constraint module, the document-type shell gets everything it needs to both define
    and constrain a vocabulary module.</li>
  </ul>
  <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="02 April 2021">
   <p>What do we need to say about extension modules?</p>
  </draft-comment>
  <p>RELAX NG grammars for DITA document-type shells, vocabulary modules, and <ph rev="2.0"
    >element-configuration modules (constraint and expansion) </ph><term outputclass="RFC-2119"
    >MAY</term> do the following:<ul>
    <li>Use the <xmlelement>a:documentation</xmlelement> element anywhere that foreign elements are
     allowed by RELAX NG. The <xmlelement>a:documentation</xmlelement> element refers to the
      <xmlelement>documentation</xmlelement> element type from the
      <xmlnsname>http://relaxng.org/ns/compatibility/annotations/1.0</xmlnsname> as defined by the
     DTD compatibility specification. The prefix "a" is used by convention.</li>
    <li>Use <xmlelement>div</xmlelement> to group pattern declarations.</li>
    <li>Include embedded Schematron rules or any other foreign vocabulary. Processors <term
      outputclass="RFC-2119">MAY</term> ignore any foreign vocabularies within DITA grammars that
     are not in the <xmlnsname>http://relaxng.org/ns/compatibility/annotations/1.0</xmlnsname> or
      <xmlnsname>http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/</xmlnsname> namespaces.</li>
   </ul></p>
  <section id="complex-vs-xml-syntax">
   <title>Syntax for RELAX NG grammars</title>
   <p>The RELAX NG specification defines two syntaxes for RELAX NG grammars: the XML syntax and the
    compact syntax. The two syntaxes are functionally equivalent, and either syntax can be reliably
    converted into the other by using, for example, the open-source Trang tool. </p>
   <p>DITA practitioners can author DITA modules using one RELAX NG syntax, and then use tools to
    generate modules in the other syntax. The resulting RELAX NG modules are conforming if there is
    a one-to-one file correspondence. </p>
   <p>Conforming RELAX NG-based DITA modules <term outputclass="RFC-2119">MAY</term> omit the
    annotations and foreign elements that are used in the OASIS grammar files to enable generation
    of other XML grammars, such as DTDs and XML Schema. When such annotations are used, conversion
    from one RELAX NG syntax to the other might lose the information, as processors are not required
    to process the annotations and information from foreign vocabularies. </p>
   <p>The DITA coding requirements are defined for the RELAX NG XML syntax. Document type shells,
    vocabulary modules, and <ph rev="2.0">element-configuration modules (constraints and
     expansion)</ph> that use the RELAX NG compact syntax can use the same organization requirements
    as those defined for the RELAX NG XML syntax. </p>
   <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="02 April 2021">
    <p>I have a problem with having a single section with a title. Either other content in this
     topic needs to be grouped into at titled section, or the original section needs to be
     removed.</p>
   </draft-comment>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept>
