<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="specialization-rules-elements" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Specialization rules for element types</title>
  <shortdesc>There are certain rules that apply to element type specializations.</shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>design and implementation rules<indexterm>element types</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>specialization<indexterm>rules<indexterm>element
          types</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <p>A specialized element type has the following characteristics:</p>
    <draft-comment author="Kristen J Eberlein" time="07 August 2022">
      <p>Robert Anderson and I both think that the 2nd bullet point needs
        expansion, to cover the effects of expansion modules.</p>
    </draft-comment>
    <ul>
      <li>A properly-formed <xmlatt>class</xmlatt> attribute that specifies the specialization
        hierarchy of the element</li>
      <li>A content model that is the same or less inclusive than that of
        the element from which it was specialized</li>
      <li>A set of attributes that are the same or a subset of those of the element from which it
        was specialized<ph rev="2.0">, except for specializations of <xmlatt>base</xmlatt> or
            <xmlatt>props</xmlatt></ph></li>
      <li>Values or value ranges of attributes that are the same or a subset of those of the element
        from which it was specialized</li>
    </ul>
    <p>DITA elements are never in a namespace. Only the <xmlatt>DITAArchVersion</xmlatt> attribute
      is in a DITA-defined namespace. All other attributes, except for those defined by the XML
      standard, are in no namespace.</p>
    <p>This limitation is imposed by the details of the <xmlatt>class</xmlatt> attribute syntax,
      which makes it impractical to have namespace-qualified names for either vocabulary modules or
      individual element types or attributes. Elements included as descendants of the DITA
        <xmlelement>foreign</xmlelement> element type can be in any namespace.</p>
    <!--IGNORE may-must-should word-->
    <note>Domain modules that are intended for wide use should define element type names that are
      unlikely to conflict with names used in other domains, for example, by using a domain-specific
      prefix on all names.</note>
  </conbody>
</concept>

