<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
 "concept.dtd">
<concept id="subjectSchema" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Subject scheme maps</title>
    <shortdesc >Subject scheme maps use key definitions to define collections
        of controlled values and subject definitions.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm>classifying content</indexterm>
                <indexterm>controlled values<indexterm>classifying content for flagging and
                        filtering</indexterm><indexterm>definition
                        of</indexterm><indexterm>overview</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>definitions<indexterm>controlled values</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>filtering and flagging<indexterm>classifying content
                    for</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>subject scheme maps<indexterm>extending</indexterm><indexterm>overview</indexterm></indexterm>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p><term>Controlled values</term> are tokens that can be used as
      values for attributes. For example, the <xmlatt>audience</xmlatt>
      attribute can take a value that identifies the users that are
      associated with a particular product. Typical values for a
      medical-equipment product line might include "therapist",
      "oncologist", "physicist", and "radiologist". In a subject scheme
      map, an information architect can define a list of these values for
      the <xmlatt>audience</xmlatt> attribute. Controlled values can be
      used to classify content for filtering and flagging at build time. </p>
        <p ><term>Subject definitions</term> are classifications and
            sub-classifications that compose a tree. Subject definitions provide  semantics that can
            be used in conjunction with taxonomies and ontologies. In conjunction with the
            classification domain, subject definitions can be used for retrieval and traversal of
            the content at run time when used with information viewing applications that provide
            such functionality.</p>
        <p >Key references to controlled values are resolved to a key
            definition using the same precedence rules as apply to any other key. However, once a
            key is resolved to a controlled value, that key reference does not typically result in
            links or generated text.</p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
