<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
 "reference.dtd">
<reference id="theformatattribute" xml:lang="en-us">
<title>The <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute</title>
<shortdesc>The <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute identifies the format of the resource that is
            referenced. <ph conkeyref="reuse-attributes/may-inherit"
            /></shortdesc>
      <prolog>
            <metadata>
                  <keywords>
                        <indexterm>attributes,
                              complex<indexterm><xmlatt>format</xmlatt></indexterm></indexterm>
                  </keywords>
            </metadata>
      </prolog>
<refbody>
<section id="section-1"><p >The following values for <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> have special processing
                        implications: </p><dl>
                        <dlentry>
                              <dt><keyword>dita</keyword></dt>
                              <dd>The destination uses DITA topic markup or markup specialized from
                        a DITA topic. Unless otherwise specified, when <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> is
                        set to <keyword>dita</keyword>, the value for the <xmlatt>type</xmlatt>
                        attribute will be treated as topic<keyword/>.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                              <dt><keyword>ditamap</keyword></dt>
                              <dd>The linked-to resource is a DITA map. It represents the referenced
                                    hierarchy at the current point in the referencing map.
                                    References to other maps can occur at any point in a map, but
                                    because relationship tables are only valid as children of a map,
                                    referenced relationship tables are treated as children of the
                                    referencing map. <note
                                          conkeyref="reuse-general/mapref-with-child-elements"
                                    /></dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                              <dt>(no value)</dt>
                              <dd>The processing default is used. The processing default for the
                            <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute is determined by inspecting the value
                        of the <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> attribute. If the <xmlatt>href</xmlatt>
                        attribute specifies a file extension, the processing default for the
                            <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute is that extension, after conversion to
                        lower-case and with no leading period. The only exception to this is if the
                        extension is <filepath>.xml</filepath>, in which case the default value for
                            <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> is <keyword>dita</keyword>. If there is no
                        extension, but the <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> value is an absolute URI whose
                        scheme is <keyword>http</keyword> or <keyword>https</keyword>, then the
                        processing default is <keyword>html</keyword>. In all other cases where no
                        extension is available, the processing default is
                            <keyword>dita.</keyword><p>If the actual format of the referenced
                            content differs from the effective value of the <xmlatt>format</xmlatt>
                            attribute, and a processor is capable of identifying such cases, it
                                <term outputclass="RFC-2119">MAY</term> recover gracefully and treat
                            the content as its actual format, but <term outputclass="RFC-2119"
                                >SHOULD</term> also issue a message.</p></dd>
                        </dlentry>
                  </dl>
             <sectiondiv id="lwdita_formats">
                <p id="p_ckq_jxh_nhb">For DITA processors that support Lightweight DITA, the
                    following values for <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> have special processing
                    implications: </p>
                <dl>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>xdita</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The format of the resource is XDITA.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>mdita</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The format of the resource is MDITA.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>hdita</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The format of the resource is HDITA. </dd>
                    </dlentry>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>xditamap</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The resource is an XDITA map.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                </dl>
                <dl>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>hditamap</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The resource is an HDITA map.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                </dl>
                <dl>
                    <dlentry>
                        <dt><keyword>mditamap</keyword></dt>
                        <dd>The resource is an MDITA map.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                </dl>
            </sectiondiv>
            <sectiondiv id="sample-formats">
                        <p>For other formats, using the file extension without the "." character
                              typically represents the format. For example, the following values are
                              all possible values for <xmlatt>format</xmlatt>:</p>
                        <dl>
                              <dlentry>
                                    <dt><keyword>html</keyword></dt>
                                    <dd>The format of the linked-to resource is HTML or XHTML.</dd>
                              </dlentry>
                              <dlentry>
                                    <dt><keyword>pdf</keyword></dt>
                                    <dd>The format of the linked-to resource is PDF.
                                          <!--Processors should open a new window.--></dd>
                              </dlentry>
                              <dlentry>
                                    <dt><keyword>txt</keyword></dt>
                                    <dd>The format of the linked-to resource is a text file.</dd>
                              </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                  </sectiondiv>
            </section>
</refbody>
</reference>
