<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="navtitle" xml:lang="en-us">
<title><xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement></title>
  <shortdesc id="shortdesc">A navigation title is an alternate title for a resource; this alternate
    title is optimized for situations where the topic title is unsuitable for use in a table of
    contents or navigation pane.</shortdesc>
<refbody>
    <section id="usage-information">
      <title>Usage information</title>
      <p>Navigation titles can be used in both topics and maps. When used in maps, a navigation
        title can serve as an alternate title or simply as an aid to understanding the DITA map.</p>
      <p platform="dita">Because the <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element is available within
          <xmlelement>topicmeta</xmlelement>,
        <!--and <xmlelement>topicmeta</xmlelement> is used in many different contexts, --> a
          <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element might occur in contexts where a navigation title
        does not make sense, for example, on a <xmlelement>topicgroup</xmlelement> element. In those
        situations, the <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element has no defined purpose.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="processing-expectations">
      <title>Processing expectations</title>
      <div platform="dita">
        <p>When the <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element is used in a topic, processors <term
            outputclass="RFC-2119">SHOULD</term> use the contents of the element to generate the
          navigation title.</p>
        <p>When the <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element is used in a map, processors <term
            outputclass="RFC-2119">SHOULD</term> retrieve the navigation title in the following order:<ol>
            <li>From the content of a <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element in the map, if the
              containing <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement> element sets the value of the
                <xmlatt>locktitle</xmlatt> attribute to "yes"</li>
            <li>From the contents of a <xmlelement>navtitle</xmlelement> element in the referenced
              topic</li>
            <li>From the title of the referenced topic</li>
          </ol></p>
        <p platform="lwdita">When the navigation title component is used in a map, processors <term
            outputclass="RFC-2119">SHOULD</term> use the contents of the component to generate the
          navigation title.</p>
      </div>
    </section>
    <section id="attributes">
      <title>Attributes</title>
      <p platform="dita">The following attributes are available on this element: <xref
          keyref="attributes-universal"/>.</p>
      <p platform="lwdita">The following attributes are available on this element: <xref
          keyref="attributes-localization"/>, <xref keyref="attributes-universal/class"
            ><xmlatt>class</xmlatt></xref>, and <xref keyref="attributes-universal/outputclass"
            ><xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt></xref>.</p>
    </section>
</refbody>
</reference>

