<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="fn" xml:lang="en-us">
<title><xmlelement>fn</xmlelement></title>
  <shortdesc id="shortdesc">A footnote is ancillary information that typically is rendered in the
    footer of a page or at the end of an online article. Such content is usually inappropriate for
    inline inclusion.</shortdesc>
<prolog><metadata>
<keywords>
    <indexterm>processing expectations<indexterm><xmlelement>fn</xmlelement></indexterm></indexterm>
</keywords>
</metadata></prolog>
<refbody>
    <section id="usage-information">
      <title>Usage information</title>
      <p>There are two types of footnotes: <term>single-use footnote</term> and
          <term>use-by-reference footnote</term>.</p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Single-use footnote</dt>
          <dd>This is produced by a <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element that does not specify a
            value for the <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Use-by-reference footnote</dt>
          <dd>This is produced by a <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element that specifies a value for
            the <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute. It must be used in conjunction with an
              <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element with <xmlatt>type</xmlatt> set to "fn."</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <p>To reference a footnote that is located in another topic, the conref mechanism is used.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="rendering-expectations">
      <title>Rendering expectations</title>
      <p>The two footnote types typically produce different types of output:</p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Single-use footnote</dt>
          <dd>When rendered, a superscript symbol (numeral or character) is produced at the location
            of the <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element. The superscript symbol is hyperlinked to the
            content of the footnote, which is placed at the bottom of a PDF page or the end of an
            online article. The superscript symbol can be specified by the value of the
              <xmlatt>callout</xmlatt> attribute. When no <xmlatt>callout</xmlatt> value is
            specified, footnotes are typically numbered.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Use-by-reference footnote</dt>
          <dd>Nothing is rendered at the location of the <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> element. The
            content of a use-by-reference footnote is only rendered when it is referenced by an
              <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> with the <xmlatt>type</xmlatt> attribute set to "fn". If
            an <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> with the <xmlatt>type</xmlatt> attribute set to "fn" is
            present, a superscript symbol is rendered at the location of the
              <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element. Unless conref is used, the
              <xmlelement>fn</xmlelement> and <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> must be located in the
            same topic.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <p>However, the details of footnote processing and formatting are implementation dependent.
        For example, a tool that renders DITA as PDF might lack support for the
          <xmlatt>callout</xmlatt> attribute, or footnotes might be collected as end notes for
        certain types of publications.</p>
    </section>
</refbody>
</reference>

