<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
 "reference.dtd">
<reference id="navref" xml:lang="en-us">
<title><xmlelement>navref</xmlelement></title>
<shortdesc>A navigation reference is a reference to another map which is preserved as a transcluding
    link in the result deliverable rather than resolved when the deliverable is produced. Output
    formats that support such linking can integrate the referenced resource when displaying the
    referencing map to an end user. </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>elements<indexterm>basic
              map<indexterm><xmlelement>navref</xmlelement></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
<refbody>
    <section id="usage-information">
      <title>Usage information</title>
      <p>The <xmlelement>navref</xmlelement> element is intended as a reference to a navigation
        resource that can be resolved at rendering time. It allows for maps to be published into a
        help system where the referenced navigation is published independently (or may not be
        avilable at all). If available, the referenced navigation can then be resolved at render
        time within a help system.</p>
      <p>In order to include another map directly without depending on the output format or help
        system, use a <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement> element with the <xmlatt>format</xmlatt>
        attribute set to <codeph>ditamap</codeph>. The effect is similar to using a
          <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> attribute. For example, the following markup represents a literal
        inclusion of the map
        <filepath>other.ditamap</filepath>:<codeblock>&lt;topicref href="other.ditamap" format="ditamap"/&gt;</codeblock></p>
    </section>
    <section id="attributes">
      <title>Attributes</title>
      <p id="universal-outputclass">The following attributes are available on this element: <ph conkeyref="reuse-attributes/ref-universalatts"/> and the attribute
        defined below.</p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt id="attr-mapref"><xmlatt>mapref</xmlatt></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the URI of the map file or non-DITA resource to be referenced. It might
            reference a DITA map or a resource that is appropriate for a target help system. <ph
              otherprops="examples">For example, it could reference an XML TOC file for use with
              Eclipse help.</ph>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
<example id="example" otherprops="examples"><title>Example</title><p>In the following code sample, the map titled "MyComponent tasks" references the maps
          <filepath>othermap2.ditamap</filepath> and <filepath>othermap3.ditamap</filepath>.</p><codeblock>&lt;map&gt;
 &lt;title>MyComponent tasks&lt;/title>
 &lt;navref mapref="../com.example.plugin.xml.doc/othermap1.ditamap"/&gt;
 &lt;navref mapref="../com.example.plugin.xml.doc/othermap2.ditamap"/&gt;
&lt;/map&gt;</codeblock></example>
</refbody>
</reference>

