<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?workdir /C:\Git\dita\specification\temp\pdf\non-normative?><?workdir-uri file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/temp/pdf/non-normative/?><?path2project ..\?><?path2project-uri ../?><?path2rootmap-uri ../?><?doctype-public -//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN?><?doctype-system concept.dtd?><concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic concept) (topic abbrev-d) a(props deliveryTarget) (topic equation-d) (topic hazard-d) (topic hi-d) (topic indexing-d) (topic markup-d) (topic mathml-d) (topic pr-d) (topic relmgmt-d) (topic sw-d) (topic svg-d) (topic ui-d) (topic ut-d) (topic markup-d xml-d)" id="nteroperability-considerations" xml:lang="en-us" xtrc="concept:1;3:63" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
  <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:1;4:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Processing interoperability considerations</title>
  <shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc " xtrc="shortdesc:1;5:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">The DITA specification does not require processors to perform filtering, content
    reference resolution, key space construction, and other processing related to base DITA
    semantics in any particular order. This means that different conforming DITA processors <ph class="- topic/ph " xtrc="ph:1;8:8" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">might</ph> produce different results for the same initial data set and
    filtering conditions. DITA users and DITA implementers need to be aware of these potential
    differences in behavior when DITA content will be processed by different processors.</shortdesc><prolog class="- topic/prolog "><author class="- topic/author " xtrc="author:1;14:11" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/dita-2.0-specification.ditamap">OASIS DITA Technical Committee</author></prolog>
  <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody " xtrc="conbody:1;11:12" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
    <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:1;12:8" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">In general, in any situation in which two elements interact during processing, applying
      filtering before or after the processing is done <ph class="- topic/ph " xtrc="ph:2;13:61" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">can</ph> result in
      different results when either or both of the elements is conditional.</p>
    <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:2;15:8" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">For conditional elements, an element is "applicable" if it is filtered in and "inapplicable"
      if it is filtered out.</p>
    <section class="- topic/section " id="filtering-and-conref-resolution" xtrc="section:1;17:51" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:2;18:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Filtering and content reference resolution</title>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:3;19:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">When two elements are merged as result of a content reference, the attributes of the two
        elements are combined. By default, the attributes of the referencing element take precedence
        over the referenced element. However, any attribute can specify the value
        "-dita-use-conref-target", which causes the referenced element attribute to take precedence.
        This means that the effective value of filtering attributes might reflect either the
        referencing element or the referenced element depending on how each attribute is configured
        on the referencing element. This in turn means that, in certain cases, filtering before
        resolving content references will produce a different result than when filtering is applied
        after resolving content references.</p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:4;28:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">In two cases, the order in which filtering is applied results in either an element being in
        the effective result or an element not being in the effective result. There is a third case
        in which there will be either an empty element (and unresolvable content reference) or no
        element. </p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:5;32:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">In the case where a referenced element is not applicable and the referencing element is
        explicitly applicable for the same condition (that is, both elements specify values for the
        same filtering attribute and the referencing element is applicable), if content references
        are resolved <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i " xtrc="i:1;35:25" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">before</i> filtering, the content reference is resolved and the effective
        value of the referencing element reflects the referenced element. If content referencing is
        resolved <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i " xtrc="i:2;37:21" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">after</i> filtering, the referenced element is filtered out and the content
        reference cannot be resolved, typically generating an error.</p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:6;39:11" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">The same scenario results in different results for the case of conref push.
        An applicable, referencing element can use conref push to replace another element that would
        otherwise be filtered out. If content references are resolved <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i " xtrc="i:3;41:74" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">before</i> filtering, the
        content is pushed and the effective value of the referenced element reflects the referencing
        element. If content referencing is resolved <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i " xtrc="i:4;43:56" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">after</i> filtering, the referenced element
        will be filtered out and the content reference can no longer be resolved.</p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:7;45:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">If the referencing element is not conditional and the referenced element is inapplicable,
        filtering applied before content reference resolution results in an unresolvable content
        reference. If filtering is applied after content resolution, the explicit condition on the
        referenced element becomes the effective value for that condition following content
        resolution and the result is then filtered out. The difference in these two cases is that in
        the first case the content reference cannot be resolved, resulting in a processing error and
        a potentially nonsensical element if the referencing element has required subelements (for
        example, a content reference from a topic to another topic, where the referencing topic must
        have a title subelement), but in the second case the element is filtered completely out.</p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:8;54:11" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Different processing orders might also provide different results in the case
        where pushed content is wrapped in an element that is filtered out. If filtering is applied
        before content resolution, that entire block of content (the wrapper and the content to be
        pushed) is filtered out before the content reference is resolved. If filtering is applied
        after content resolution, the push action will be resolved first so that content appears in
        the referenced location, after which the referencing element (along with its wrapper) is
        filtered from the original source location.</p>
    </section>
    <section class="- topic/section " id="filtering-and-key-space-resolution" xtrc="section:2;62:54" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:3;63:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Filtering and key space resolution</title>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:9;64:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">See <xref class="- topic/xref " href="../archSpec/base/processing-key-references-general.dita#processing_key_references/keys-and-condproc" xtrc="xref:1;66:11" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita" type="section"><?ditaot gentext?>Keys and conditional processing</xref> for a discussion of effective key definitions and conditional processing.</p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:10;67:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">As an implementation detail for key-space-constructing processors, if filtering is applied
        before constructing the key space, then the set of effective key definitions is simply the
        first definition of each unique key name. However, if filtering is applied after key space
        construction, and in particular, if a processor needs to allow dynamic resolution of keys
        based on different filtering specifications applied to the same constructed key space, then
        the set of effective key definitions is the first definition of each pair of unique key name
        and unique selection specification set. This second form of constructed key space would be
        needed by processors such as editors and content management systems that need to quickly
        provide different filtering-specific key bindings without reconstructing the entire key
        space for each new set of filtering conditions. </p>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:11;77:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">For example, given a map that contains two definitions for the key "topic-01", one with an
          <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:1;78:19" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">audience</xmlatt> value of "expert" and one with an <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:2;78:79" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">audience</xmlatt>
        value of "novice", a filter-first processor would only have at most one effective key
        definition for the key name "topic-01", whichever of the two definitions was filtered in by
        the active filter specification and was the first definition encountered (if both happen to
        be filtered in). In a processor that supports dynamic key definition filtering, there would
        be two effective definitions for the key name "topic-01", one for <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:3;83:83" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">audience</xmlatt>
        of "expert" and one for <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:4;84:41" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">audience</xmlatt> of "novice". The processor would also need
        to maintain knowledge of the definition order of the two key definitions in order to
        correctly handle the case when both "expert" and "novice" are applicable for a given key
        access request (in which case, whichever of the two definitions was first would be used as
        the effective value of the key).</p>
    </section>
    <section class="- topic/section " id="link-resolution" xtrc="section:3;90:35" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:4;91:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Link resolution</title>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:12;92:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">If a cross reference, link, or other linking element is resolved to its target before
        filtering and the target is subsequently filtered out, the link would be to a non-existent
        target but might reflect properties of the target (for example, a cross reference link text
        might reflect the target title). If the link is resolved after filtering is applied and the
        target is filtered out, the link is to a non-existent target, which will result in a
        different link text. The rendition effect for the navigation link is the same: the link
        cannot be navigated because the target does not exist in the rendered result.</p>
    </section>
    
    <section class="- topic/section " id="topicref-resolution" xtrc="section:4;101:39" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:5;102:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Topicref resolution</title>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:13;103:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Resolution of topicrefs before filtering can result in use of topic-provided navigation
        titles or metadata that would not be used if the target topic was filtered out before
        resolution. In both cases, the topicref as rendered would be to a missing topic. </p>
    </section>
    
    <section class="- topic/section " id="copy-to-processing" xtrc="section:5;108:38" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">
      <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:6;109:14" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">Copy-to processing</title>
      <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:14;110:10" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">If copy-to processing is done before filtering, two <xmlelement class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlelement " xtrc="xmlelement:1;110:74" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">topicref</xmlelement>
        elements, only one of which is applicable, could specify the same <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:5;111:83" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">copy-to</xmlatt>
        target, leading to a conflict and a potential ambiguity about which governs. If the
          <xmlelement class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlelement " xtrc="xmlelement:2;113:23" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">topicref</xmlelement> elements are filtered before <xmlatt class="+ topic/keyword markup-d/markupname xml-d/xmlatt " xtrc="xmlatt:6;113:82" xtrf="file:/C:/Git/dita/specification/non-normative/interoperability-considerations.dita">copy-to</xmlatt>
        processing, the conflict does not occur.</p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>